<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Broken Shadow Maps</title>
    <link>https://example.com/projects/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Broken Shadow Maps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/projects/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SDF Generator for Unity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/tech/sdfgen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/tech/sdfgen/</guid>
      <description>Writing SDFs by hand is fun! But it can be a slow and arduous process.
This tool is an signed distance field (SDF) code generator running inside Unity.
It lets the user make and combine distance functions to make interesting scenes inside an intuitive editor such as Unity. It then tries to optimize the code for specific known cases (for example, it tries to prevent using matrices when dealing with planes), but it is far from complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedural Rubik City</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/tech/rubik/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/tech/rubik/</guid>
      <description>A short code-only demo based on &amp;ldquo;To the Moon&amp;rdquo;, by Dunderpatrullen. Done with three.JS and WebGL. Every element is procedurally generated. The buildings are generated by a set of randomized vertex layouts, and the roads are a basic voronoi spliced by a rubik&amp;rsquo;s cube grid.
This was done as an assignment for a procedural graphics class I took at the University of Pennsylvania. It also required having some post processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Projects - UPenn</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/tech/penn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/tech/penn/</guid>
      <description>While doing my Computer Graphics and Game Technology Master&amp;rsquo;s at the University of Pennsylvania, I focused on a set of projects that were particularly aligned with my interests. Mostly I used them as a way to improve my skills, explore new ideas and as an excuse to just have fun. These were all done between 2016 and 2017.
Procedural Computer Graphics (CIS 5660) Angels &amp;amp; Men A quick 1 week project done in three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InstanceAlongCurve</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/tech/instancealongcurve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/tech/instancealongcurve/</guid>
      <description>instanceAlongCurve is a Maya plugin developed in Python that tries to simplify the process of instancing various objects along a curve. The plugin essentially creates a new DAG node which handles all the necessary logic. It also includes a node creation command and a very familiar and user friendly interface.
I built this in 2015 because Maya didn&amp;rsquo;t provide an intuitive way to do curve instancing. MASH was also being integrated around that time, and although it is pretty powerful, it is a heavier process and not as streamlined as I&amp;rsquo;d prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[VR Jam 2013] Singular Journey</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/tech/singular-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/tech/singular-journey/</guid>
      <description>With Manuel Araoz we participated on the first VR Jam held by Oculus by the time the first DK1 was released. We built a walking simulator with some puzzles, and focused on ambiance and immersion.
I learned a long-lasting lesson with this project: we didn&amp;rsquo;t playtest it enough so the jam reviewers could not get past an early point in the game &amp;ndash; missing the most fun bits. This was a failure of both lack of playtesting and just bad UX/design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Projects - ITBA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/projects/tech/itba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/projects/tech/itba/</guid>
      <description>Around 2012, while finishing my Software Engineering degree at Instituto Tecnológico de Buenos Aires, I worked on a couple of graphics-related projects that were a lot of fun. These projects solidified my interest in graphics, gamedev and what would later become AR/VR.
Candylicious For ITBA&amp;rsquo;s game development class, I worked on a couple of simple game projects that got featured in the university&amp;rsquo;s technology fair. It was a great opportunity to work on both technical and art aspects of small games &amp;ndash; I did all the art and wrote all the shaders for both (aside from some of the gameplay).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
