<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Broken Shadow Maps</title>
    <link>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Broken Shadow Maps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Door of Night</title>
      <link>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/door-of-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/door-of-night/</guid>
      <description>An homage to John Howe&amp;rsquo;s Door of Night, which was originally done for Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s The Book of Lost Tales. The original illustration was one of my earliest inspirations that got me into fantasy and digital art.
Featured on the Tolkien Gateway
Originally started as a project for a class I took in 2017, I had to put this project on the side throughout many years, iterating over it slowly and redesigning it over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC Police Headquarters</title>
      <link>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/headquarters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/headquarters/</guid>
      <description>Featured in 3D World and 80LV
A reconstruction of an old neoclassical building that used to be New York&amp;rsquo;s Police Headquarters (240 Centre Street building).
Around 2018 I was sent by Framestore to the NY offices to work on a Magic Leap project. I was walking near Little Italy around golden hour, looked up and became mesmerized by a really cool piece of architecture. I was able to take a quick picture and moved on, but the image &amp;ndash; the feeling of its volume &amp;ndash; still persisted, so I eventually decided to rebuild it digitally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical/Mystical Moments</title>
      <link>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/magical-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/magical-moments/</guid>
      <description>Featured in CG@Penn&amp;rsquo;s
A reconstruction of University of Pennsylvania&amp;rsquo;s College Hall, in a magical, atmospheric winter setting. Done for the SIG lab&amp;rsquo;s Holiday Card.
More WIP renders on my ArtStation
The most fun aspect of this project was modeling it: I took my learnings from my previous Deconstruction render and focused on modeling each wall brick and each roof tile.
Personally, I think that a huge aspect of believability comes from irregularities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deconstruction</title>
      <link>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/deconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/deconstruction/</guid>
      <description>Featured in 3DArtist
A course project with the objective of reproducing a photograph. The reference image is a picture I took in Philadelphia.
A lot of care was taken to match the camera perspective, the correct illumination of that specific day and time, the shadow silhouette of objects out of the frame, the reflections of the windows and the lighting contribution of the environment, and of course the models &amp;amp; surfaces in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canova&#39;s Eurydice</title>
      <link>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/eurydice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/eurydice/</guid>
      <description>An interpretation of Eurydice based on an original sculpture by Antonio Canova in 1776.
A lot of iterations were made to the lighting of this piece, to emphasize Eurydice and Orpheus&amp;rsquo;s story &amp;ndash; I applied concepts used in museum lighting.
This was done as an assignment for Penn&amp;rsquo;s Introduction to Modeling course. To be fair to my fellow student friends, however, I was already slightly experienced in digital human anatomy. The class&amp;rsquo;s human project let me dig deeper and sharpen my skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/old-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmerchante.github.io/projects/art/old-stuff/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of old finished renders that were formative in my 3D journey.
Story time: I started learning 3D when I was 13, around 2003. At the time, it was really hard to find tutorials and resources to learn, particularly in accessible in spanish.
Because of that, one of the things I focused on while learning was also reinterpreting and translating tutorials to spanish. I decided to contribute with various 3D tutorials to DiseñAr, a long gone (but fairly active at that time) argentinian design tutorial website, which also let me learn the basics of teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
